Hello Good afternoon Good morning
everyone This is mausi and Welcome to
mai's channel wherein I write
about personal Finance and Mental Health
awareness or whatever I want to
talk about So today
we will talk about my 10 year
Journey with my Sun Life maxing crie
so just um a disclaimer I'm not in any
way affiliated with ah with sun life and
I'm not a financial Planner and I'm also
not a financial advisor Finance advisor
So this is just primarily because I am
um a client who wants to share
what my experience was with
getting Sun Life um maxilink Prime
or the also known as vul okay the one
we often hear is vul so I
will start with the background
when I first got it 10 years ago
that was March
2015 and I have a colleague at work
who introduced me to the product
sunlife maxilink Prime Well
I really don't know what
those V's are life
insurance but that's why I got it It's
because um I was an orphaned  or that
my father passed away when I was just 3
years old and during that time 10 years
ago I just gave birth to
my son ah He was born way
back
2014 July so when I was offered
2015 I was offered around y March
so He's just around 8 months old so
I thought that I wanted him to have
security Actually I really didn't
care about the investment side because as
we all know it or for those who are not familiar with
the vul is a combination of life
insurance and um investment Okay so at that
time what I was really worried about
was the insurance side I really didn't
care about investment Dal I
am not that um educated yet when it comes
to investment as long as I found out
what would happen to me the 8
months old he was only or if it was us or
whatever it was for me because I'm
sure I want
my son to get something at least during
that time because who knows we don't
know um When will
um sad What What do you call that  um um
What is it What does it mean sad
sickness accident and worst is
that you're taken out of the picture and
that would be death which is or which
was happened down there to my father so
I took certain face value I won't
say what it is just so that someone can
get my son whatever
happens because we really don't
know 'ba so as time goes by I'm not
too I don't look at him too much
Actually if but it
also came to the point maybe 2017 or 2018
asked I was also wondering if because
I pay him quarterly 'ba
religiously I pay quarterly so it
came to the point I looked at him this is
that Actually
Yeah this is the
um What is this called a proposal Okay these are
the things
I signed there so it is him So because
I see a lot of that Oh why is
my investment side like this is like this like that
So down there I 2018 or 2017
literally was the year
I became financially curious that's when I
started asking if to
investment or whatever then I worry
not just  It turns out that
this insurance is not
just insurance so I know it
has an investment side but I really
didn't
um gave too much attention with regards
to the investment part so there it is
and ah I just didn't really
understand it so my Riders are Please
check on
it
[Music]
okay let's go
a is Don't do it
when you're already
studying it when
you're in the middle Okay because that's what
I did basically that's what I did
so my Rider here is total disability
benefit and Accidental death
dismemberment and disablement benefit So
if you see there's no critical
no critical illness later
we'll tag what I did there Okay so
my investment side is on the
camera There my investment side
is on the balance fund so when
I understood it the balance fund
is a combination of something like
equity fixed income ah ah what else are the
combinations there I
found out that there are other things
you can put on the investment side of
your vul that would be more suitable Especially when
you're a little more  You're still young Okay so
I've been studying and investing in the stock
market and other
investment vehicles and then When I
spoke to my Finance advisor, Attorney Sandra Aava, I really made a special comment or
special mention to her.
If you wanted to have a Finance
advisor, please feel free to message me
so I'll give you to
her okay because I really did it when
I was asking maybe 202 or I
don't know the time when
I was asking with regards to this one because that's what
I told you when
I was there I mean
I was halfway through my Journey I
really just asked questions So
I asked a lot of questions to her So the Ine effect is what
I understood or what I did is
I continued this vul because
what I understand here is life
insurance insurance and the vul or I
mean the investment part so at first
you really don't
feel like you're investing
okay that's the misconception. At first you
really only pay full on insurance, you
pay insurance fees or
whatever
but when I got to the  sixth
year sth year that I'm down I feel that it's
adding to the
fund value Okay that's the fund value or
investment side I mentioned a while
ago that it was Uh invested in balance
fund I moved it into index fund
because I'm still young so I still
have that Horizon that I can still
work I can still add to it
because the index fund ah would be the top
30 companies in the philippines so it's in the
stock market so I didn't
go down to balance because the
balance Because Ah the
balance fund is lower risk is lower its risk
its return is also lower but
when I moved it to index
fund there its risk is quite high the
um possibility of falling or going down
But its return is also higher in
the long run and index fund is more suitable
when your Horizon is far away or long that
you can work
You can drop or save on it So question
um I just paid it
religiously up to um Actually it was 7
year or 8th year that I stopped
paying the standard for example
your quarterly for example just is  6,000
so on my 8th year let's just say he has reached
the amount that you need to pay is
240,000 or How much is it? So when you reach
that, you can actually not
pay the amount that you have covered
the entire
um entire fee or I mean the entire value of the
insurance policy that you took out. So at
the 8th year 8 or 7 I'm not good in
dates but just at a certain point
I stopped paying the amount
quarterly because I can take it
from the fund value Okay so what I'm going to do is
instead of let's just say 6,000
I'm just putting away per year or
whenever I have money 2,000
3,000 to add to
my main investment side which is already in
the
um the index fund so that's it until
I reach the 10th year now
Okay so that's it and until
um until after 10
years you'll still pay but not
necessarily your premium  in my
Example 6,000 is not 6,000 so when
you are a paper worker just so that
what is in your fund value doesn't run out So for example
you have 200,000 down in your fund value
ah but you didn't pay or you didn't
add after 10 years you
just get rid of the 200,000
fee which is my fee is Php25 6
per month because
that is what is also paid one of what
we pay in the vul the one who
takes care of it or
there is like a manager there is a
service in sunlight in the IO so we can't
really
get rid of it Okay so going back
I reviewed it too and there was no
critical illness in what I took um
I continued the vul and at the same
time I took out Sun Life assure So it's
like it's just an addition to
my
ah what is this called my benefit or
um my protection so I have sun life
maxilink Prime and now I pay every year
the term insurance sort of a
term insurance which is Sun Life
assure so it's important while
my child is still young right  I have life
insurance because when your child is still small,
the Ah what you call that
responsibility or dependency on you is greater.
So now I'm happy because
my child is 1 and Ah happy to say that
nothing has happened yet. I
hope not, but at least as
the child gets older or as your children get older,
your life insurance becomes more like a
backup, not the
Ah I mean they're on their way.
They're going there. They're getting older too
and they're also gaining
consciousness so that in the long run
they also have the capacity to live or think for
themselves. Okay so that's it. Um
That's How My 10 years right now and um
just to add. I have a loyalty
gift from them which is
around 2,000 or 2,500 plus as long as
they give you those gifts for 10 years. Okay
so is Sun Life maxing
Prime advisable? If you know by term or
if you know the stock market,
well, I can't stop you. Um you can do
beauty ID. I'll try to to
to.
um give that or discuss that one as well it's
good because you just pay
for the term and then you have um term
insurance then you have um
investment side But if you totally have nothing nothing
you
really have nothing nothing you don't know This is
good because he is a protector Don't
think about the investment side the
protection side is the most expensive
for him You have your children
especially if they are still small okay or
you have children if you are single and
you have children and you
want them to be covered that's also good
that you have this Okay so what
I always say do your own research dior
and um take your own risk when you are
investing or you put your money
in any investment vehicle
Okay so I hope this video makes sense So
now what will happen after
my 10 years ah
I will just pay Php25 6 or whatever amount is
deducted from my fund value ah
my whole life until age I think 80 like that
so my whole life is on
um I
mean open I mean open the or or
I can use my life insurance okay
So for now I'm paying  I make about 3,000 to
5,000 per year when I have money to
cover the fees and at the same
time supplement what is in my life
insurance or index fund
investment side of my policy Okay so if
you have any questions is there anything unclear in what
I said I'm sorry Um and if you do
have any com
or whatever Please feel free to comment
down below and let's answer that along
with all the people who
can watch this vlog again this
is ma's channel i am mk and thank you
for supporting this channel please
subscribe Don't forget to subscribe and
like my video byby